Yihan (Tony) Xu 1536 Kerley Dr, San Jose, CA 95112

Mobile: +1-626-898-1388 Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/tonyxu93

Email: yihan.xu@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Versatile solutions engineer with strong engineering background and 2+ years solution engineering experience. Passionate working with users, customers, and engineers. Resolve customer problems in a working, efficient, and scalable way. Excited to be exposed with new technologies and always be ready to learn, master and introduce to customers. Dedicated to providing best solution for customers to achieve smooth user experience.

EXPERIENCE

LinkedIn

Sunnyvale, CA

Partner Engineer - LinkedIn Sales Solutions

June, 2018 - Present

• Partner Engineering: Provide expert consultation to partners with regard to LinkedIn platform API/SDKs

Moxtra, Inc

Cupertino, CA

Software Engineer - Solutions Engineering

Feb, 2016 - May, 2018

- Solutions Engineering: Lead engagement with BD and engineering team from pre-sales through RFI/RFP, SOW, solution design, testing, and deployment; Support strategic accounts for integration implementation and troubleshooting production issues with Moxtra Collaboration API/SDK; Collaborate with engineering and product team daily to update architecture diagrams, user guides, internal WiKi, and developer documentation.
- Software Development: Independently implemented 4 integration with third-party services to enable Moxtra capabilities; Built POC for prospects and partners using React/Javascript/Objective-C/REST-API; Built internal tools for platform using Python/Node.js to improve operation efficiency and optimized operation workflow.

University of Missouri - Operations Department

Columbia, MO

Project Manager

Jan, 2016 - May, 2016

- **Project Management:** Directed development team of 9 developers and drive 15 university website projects from concept to delivery. Conducted training for university employee users. Mentored new team members team procedures and technical tasks.
- Software Engineering: Define software engineering strategy and technology stack. Master full lifecycle of development, testing, and deployment.

SINA (NASDAQ)

Beijing, China

Assistant Product Manager Intern

Mar 2014 - June 2014

- **Product Management:** Researched user needs, translated business use cases into product requirements, developed prototypes and launched products; Collaborate with cross-functional teams on projects from design, initiate new products and drive to general availability.
- **Product Growth:** Built successful product in new platform and met year-end target within 3 months, boosted customer retention by 25% and traffic by 50%.

Projects

- Moxtra Chrome Extension for Google Mail and Calendar: Used Javascript, React, REST API, Node.js, Gulp to build Chrome extension applications that embed Moxtra chat/meeting capabilities into Gmail and Calendar.
- Moxtra Outlook Add-in: Cooporated with Microsoft Office API, Javascript, and Moxtra REST API to build mailbox and appointment calendar integrations to allow users to collaborate with Moxtra contacts.
- Moxtra Trello Power-up: Work with Trello team to build and introduce Trello power-up for Moxtra, enabling millions of Trello users to gain chat and meeting capability provided by Moxtra API/SDK.

EDUCATION

University of Missouri - Columbia

Master of Science in Computer Science

Columbia, MO

Aug. 2014 - Dec. 2016

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China

Bachelor of Engineering in Software Engineering

Chengdu, China Aug. 2011 – July. 2015